Iano Njuguna

Thika, Kiambu, Kenya



inc3099@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ianonjuguna

Summary

I am a highly skilled software developer with two years of experience, I have honed my skills in various programming languages, tools, and frameworks.

I have a strong background in problem-solving and have developed the ability to work effectively in a team environment. In addition to my technical skills, I have expertise in technical writing and digital marketing, which I utilize to write a technical blog and as a Technical Translator for the freeCodeCamp Swahili Localization project.

I am equipped to build software solutions for a wide range of industries and businesses, with a focus on automating tasks and providing valuable services.

Experience



(A) Technical Translator

freeCodeCamp

Jun 2022 - Present (9 months)

- I translate complex technical documents from English to Kiswahili for the Swahili localization project.
- · I incorporate both technical vernacular and cultural facets of the language while maintaining the original document formatting and layout.
- I meet translation deadlines and provide on-time delivery of all content with accuracy and efficiency.

Technical Writer

Hashnode

Apr 2022 - Present (11 months)

- I publish technical articles on what I learn.
- I focus on content that adds value to the tech community.
- I develop a user-friendly layout to ensure readers effortlessly understand technical content.

Software Engineer

alx_africa

Mar 2022 - Present (1 year)

- 1. I gain a theoretical understanding of software engineering principles, including software design, architecture, and testing methodologies.
- 2. I apply practical skills in software design and implementation, including the use of software development tools and technologies.
- 3. I identify software requirements and translate them into functional specifications.
- 4. I have developed proficiency in software installation and configuration, as well as troubleshooting and problem-solving techniques.

5. I use best practices for managing software projects, including version control, project management tools, and team collaboration.

Enumerator

Kenya National Bureau of Statistics

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019 (3 months)

- I canvassed the Muthaiga area of Kiganjo in Thika to conduct accurate and timely survey data collection of over 10,000 residents and 3,500 properties through door-to-door interviews according to established standards.
- I interpreted interview questions to assist people in understanding them and providing eloquent answers.
- I verified, compiled, recorded, and coded the derived data into a predefined database.

Education



Mount Kenya University - MKU

Bachelor of Laws - LLB May 2021 - Dec 2021

Africa Nazarene University

Bachelor of Laws - LLB Aug 2017 - Mar 2020

🙀 Kagumo High School

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education Feb 2013 - Dec 2016

Skills

Translation • Linguistics • C (Programming Language) • Linux • Collaborative Problem Solving • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Microsoft Word • Microsoft PowerPoint • Research